# Paul Fisher

#### PhD Researcher

I am a researcher in Cognitive Neuroscience specialising in statistics and vision research with extensive experience of Machine Learning tools in both Python and MATLAB. I have a strong background in data-science where I developed advanced frequentist and bayesian statistical skills. My research has been published in reputable scientific journals on topics such as MRI Imaging with ML SVMs where I contributed code to international collaborative research team projects. My Master's Thesis was also guided by my research knowledge on contemporary K-Fold cross-validation techniques. I am determined to advance my career in the world of data-science and have recently begun documenting my portfolio of projects on Github and my website.

p.fisher@psy.lmu.de

Munich

in linkedin.com/in/paul-fisher-munich

+4917624698714

pauliou.github.io

github.com/pauLiou

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Ph.D Researcher - Vision** LMU, Munich

06/2019 - Present

- Published in high impact scientific journals.
- Experience with Python, R, and MATLAB to perform data analysis tasks and semiautomation of data pipelines. (Capturing, cleaning, transforming, visualising).
- Advanced statistical skills including inferential and bayesian statistical models, psychometrics, and behavioural hypothesis testing

### **Data Science Research Assistant**

LMU, Munich

01/2018 - 12/2018

- Semi-automated data pipeline involving data collection, preprocessing, and data transformation using EEGlab and R.
- Project management including recruitment of EEG participants, experiment design (Python), and testing.
- Mentoring Bachelor students.

### **Machine Learning Research Assistant**

PRONIA team, Munich

11/2017 - 10/2018

- Masters Thesis Support Vector Machine and Out of Sample Cross Validation of Schizophrenia structural brain images looking for biomarkers (MATLAB).
- Neuropsychological test data management.

#### **Clinical Research Assistant**

German Center for Vertigo and Balance Disorders

01/2017 - 12/2017

- Prototyping point-of-care application for bedside testing of spatial orientation and memory (Published).
- End user testing for UAT research, data collection and analysis (SPSS and EXCEL).

## **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Science - Neuro-Cognitive Psychology

LMU, Munich - First Class Honours

10/2016 - 06/2018

#### **Bachelor of Science - Psychology**

Canterbury Christ Church University - First Class Honours

10/2013 - 06/2016

# **SKILLS**



#### **PROJECTS**

# Image Classification using Xception ML 95% Accuracy

Able to predict real world examples with high accuracy. https://pauliou.github.io/project\_image\_classifier

# Deep Learning for Titanic Competition on Kaggle

78% Accuracy (top 15% in competition leaderboard). Utilises custom parameter refinement effectively. https://pauliou.github.io/project\_titanic

#### R Shiny App designed from scratch

Can run correlations, t-tests, parametrics, descriptives. Outputs publishable quality figures. https://pauliou.github.io/project\_r\_shiny

#### COVID Statistics using Tableau

Dashboard showcasing simple visualisation techniques https://pauliou.github.io/project\_tableau

# **PROGRAMMING SKILLS**

Python (2016 - Present)

NumPy Pandas Tensorflow Keras Matplotlib Scikit-Learn

R Studio (2018 - Present)

nlme sistats Rmisc dplyr gqplot2 rstatix Shiny

MATLAB (2017 - Present)

Psychtoolbox

SQL (2021 - Present)

SSMS PopSql

### **CERTIFICATES**

Intro to Deep Learning (2022) *Kaggle* 

Computer Vision (2022)

Kaggle